<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Things I have seen</title>
    <link>https://niciliketo.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Things I have seen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-GB</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 07:46:19 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://niciliketo.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Retrieval Augmented Generation</title>
      <link>https://niciliketo.github.io/2023/09/retrieval-augmented-generation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Sep 2023 07:46:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://niciliketo.github.io/2023/09/retrieval-augmented-generation/</guid>
      <description>I want to implement a RAG system that will index a set of documents and then answer questions based on them. My plan is to use our ISO27001 ISMS documents to answer security questions from suppliers.
The basic plan was
 Build it inside docker Use Langchain to make it all work Use ElasticSearch for the retrieval part Use Open AI API initially, but hopefully a local LLM in the future  Here is the GitHub repo</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SaaS Reporting</title>
      <link>https://niciliketo.github.io/2022/08/saas-reporting/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Aug 2022 09:30:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://niciliketo.github.io/2022/08/saas-reporting/</guid>
      <description>Reporting requirements for a SaaS product often become more important as customer size increases. Enterprise Ready have a great article explaining this.
Below I have attempted to summarise my experience building a single instance, multi-tenant SaaS solution.
 challenges we see things we have done so far approaches we may consider in future  Challenges User experience Users are familiar with creating reports with tools such as Excel and Tableau. They expect a similar quality of experience from a SaaS reporting tool.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cherished Beliefs</title>
      <link>https://niciliketo.github.io/2021/02/cherished-beliefs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Feb 2021 18:23:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://niciliketo.github.io/2021/02/cherished-beliefs/</guid>
      <description>I listened to a new Podcast today (it was a recommendation from Twitter).
You are not so smart
The episode was part 1 of 3 on The Backfire Effect. It seems like there are some uncertainty whether this is a real thing, but the episode was interesting.
It covered recent research on what happens in your brain when your beliefs are challenged. They gave examples of two types of belief.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Networking Head to Head</title>
      <link>https://niciliketo.github.io/2021/02/networking-head-to-head/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 11:41:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://niciliketo.github.io/2021/02/networking-head-to-head/</guid>
      <description>Today I want to do a head to head review of two networking solutions.
Background I am fortunate enough to live in a house. I am also fortunate that the house has plenty of space in it and is divided up by walls.
If that wasn&amp;rsquo;t enough I am also blessed by a 35Mbps internet connection.
First world problem I am unfortunate that the internet connection is in one corner on the ground floor of my house, while my desk and computer are in the opposite corner on the first floor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Valentines Day</title>
      <link>https://niciliketo.github.io/2021/02/valentines-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Feb 2021 08:03:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://niciliketo.github.io/2021/02/valentines-day/</guid>
      <description>Tip of the day If you are writing two valentines cards, to two different people and they are different sizes. Make sure you don&amp;rsquo;t write the wrong name on the envelope!
Trick of the day (Hugo) I found that following the README for the Ananke theme was quite helpful. Especially copying the config.toml from the example site, which magically made the About and Posts menu items appear. It also allowed me to add links to some social sites and customise the home and about pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My new blog</title>
      <link>https://niciliketo.github.io/2021/02/my-new-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Feb 2021 12:09:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://niciliketo.github.io/2021/02/my-new-blog/</guid>
      <description>I wanted to try using a static site generator. Github has native support for Jekyll so to make it more interesting I decided to use Hugo.
I am experimenting with Docker at the moment to avoid installing heaps of things on my computer.
GitHub I created a github repo here, according to GitHub&amp;rsquo;s Instructions
I then cloned it locally using the Code link in the repo&amp;hellip;
Installation There is a docker image for hugo listed in the installation instructions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
